## Stefan Eilemann

Faubourg de l'Hôpital 12 · CH-2000 Neuchâtel · +41 76 33 77 247 · eilemann@gmail.com

Profile

Senior software engineer and architect, with a specialization in high performance 3D graphics, C++, parallelization of applications and distributed systems. Consultant and contractor delivering solutions and expertise to enhance existing applications and to create new software.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer, 3D Graphics Neuchâtel, Switzerland January 2007 - current

Responsible for the design and development of scalable, parallel graphics applications and middleware, primarily based on Equalizer and Chromium.

Researcher, Parallel Rendering Zürich, Switzerland

University of Zürich March 2005 - current

**Tungsten Graphics** 

Initiated and developed Equalizer, a framework for distributed, scalable graphics software. Current research includes new algorithms for the parallelization, management and loadbalancing of applications on multiuser graphic clusters.

Senior Software Engineer Neuchâtel, Switzerland

Esmertec AG January 2004 – September 2005

Developed Java software in Esmertec's R&D group which enables user interface customization on mobile devices and desktops. Designed and implemented a fully functional 3D phone simulator for customer presentations.

Senior Software Engineer Neuchâtel, Switzerland

Silicon Graphics, Inc. August 2000 - December 2003

Worked in SGI's advanced graphics division as technical lead for OpenGL Multipipe SDK (MPK). MPK is a C/C++framework to develop high performance, scalable visualization software. Worked on DataSync, a distributed shared memory API for clusters.

 $Software\ Engineer$ Munich, Germany

Freelancer April 2000 - July 2000

Wrote a network configuration management solution for the internet backbone of Cable & Wireless, using Linux, Apache, MySQL and Perl.

Software Engineer Wessling, Germany

Intec GmbH October 1998 – March 2000

Worked as software engineer in the software development team for SIMPACK, a multibody simulation program. Responsible for maintaining the existing 2D and 3D graphics subsystem based on PHIGS, as well rewriting it to use Open Inventor.

Latest version at http://www.equalizergraphics.com/documents/CV\_Stefan\_Eilemann.pdf

Particulars Date of Birth 9th August 1975

Birth Place Wittenberg, Germany Nationality German, Swiss Permit C

EDUCATION Berufakademie Heidenheim

Dipl.-Ing. (eq BS) in Computer Science, September 1998

Lucas-Cranach-Gymnasium Wittenberg

Abitur (university entrance qualification), June 1994

## Expertise

- High performance OpenGL applications, concurrent programming, distributed systems, immersive environments.
- Software design, development and maintenance using C++, Java, Perl in various programming environments.
- Software development methodology during the whole lifecycle, ranging from requirements analysis, specification, design, implementation to documentation, education, debugging, profiling and support.
- In-depth knowledge of standard graphics technologies, including OpenGL, OpenGL Multipipe SDK, OpenSceneGraph, graphics hardware
- Broad knowledge of operating systems (Mac OS X, Linux (x86/IA64), Irix, Windows) and distributed computing.
- Native german speaker, fluent english, good french knowledge.

References are available on request.